Manu KM

Kazhunnukandathil (H) Ramapuram, Kottayam Kerala, India

Pin: 686576

Email:manumanmadhan95@gmail.com

Phone No: +91- 9744989651

+91-8281043582

Date of Birth: 10 March 1995



Objective

I am a *Senior Accountant* with extensive experience in fiscal operations, Business administrations, A/P, A/R, cost allocation, month/year- end closing, variance analysis, and development implementation of procedures and policies. Demonstrated expertise in strategic planning forecasting, Budgeting, financial auditing, project management and complex tax issue. Thoroughly deals-oriented with strong team leadership and collaboration skills. I would like to have a position within a growth-oriented, forward-thinking organization where I can help achieve its objectives by utilizing my experience, skills, and education to the fullest extent.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Positive Accounting Solution Junior Accountant

Ernakulum, Kerala May 2015 – September 2017

- ❖ Manage accounts payable and accounts receivable.
- ❖ Return filling of various tax return (TDS, Sales, Income Tax, Service Tax, GST).
- ❖ Maintain, analyze and reconcile all accounts and related entries on a daily and monthly basis.
- ❖ Examine journal entries, general ledgers and other document financial business transactions.
- ❖ Strong skills in Payroll management.
- Monitor and review accounting and related system records for accuracy and completeness.
- ❖ Preparation and maintenance of various registers like purchase registers, sales register and journal register etc.
- ❖ Computation and E-filling of EPF&ESI monthly return.

Phoeniex Studios Star Big Cinemas Mumbai SENIOR ACCOUNTANT

Mumbai, India November 2017 – March 2020

- ❖ Return filling of various tax return (TDS, Sales, Income Tax, Service Tax, GST).
- Strong skills in Payroll management.
- ❖ Computation and E-filling of EPF&ESI monthly return.
- ❖ Reviewed, evaluated, and ran audits on the company's existing accounting workflows; motivated to constantly improve accuracy and timeliness of record-keeping and reporting.
- ❖ Instituted checks and balances to make sure the routing of information remained efficient between the auditors, accounting teams, and finance officers.
- ❖ Coordinated with the accounting department for the purpose of ensuring the consistent precision of all operating systems, accounting networks, and processes.
- ❖ Collaborated with the IT department during the implementation of change management policies.
- ❖ Communicated with representatives of the internal and external auditing committees to foster strong, mutually beneficial relationships.

JOSE KAPPEN & CO. (Charted Accountants) Thodupuzha ,Kerala ACCOUNTANT June 2020 – Present

- ❖ Return filling of various tax return (TDS, Sales, Income Tax, Service Tax, GST).
- Statutory Audit, Finalization of Accounts.

Education

Institute/ College	Course	University	Period of study	Percentage/Marks
College of Applied Science Thodupuzha	ВСОМ	MG University	2012-2015	65
Co - Operative College Thodupuzha	Plus Two	Kerala	2010-2012	67
St. Joseph HS Manathoor	10	Kerala	2009-2010	71

Technical Skills

- ❖ Advanced ERP experience (Tally ERP 9, Tally ERP 7.2)
- * Advanced Excel ability.
- * Knowledge of Winman Software.
- Strong skills in PowerPoint, Word.

INTERNSHIP & TRAINING Programs

❖ Tally Certificate – Tally Academy

PERSONAL SKILLS

Coordinating, Quick grasping power, Co-operative and adaptive, Dedicated and Open, Caring and friendly, Positive Attitude, Good team player, Punctual, Interest in learning new things.

REFERENCES

Runnu Khandawal

Assistant Manager – Phoeniex Studios Star Big Cinemas Mumbai. 91-7738431022

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name : Manu K M

Father's Name : Manmadhan K N

Nationality : Indian

Languages : English, Hindi, Malayalam

Gender : Male
Marital Status : Single
Passport Number : S4999562

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above cited information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Manu KM

Place: Ramapuram Signature

Date: